Adam Coryat

Summary

Mr. Coryat is a Web Developer with experience in building applications with JavaScript, Vue.js, Node.js, .Net and C#. He recently graduated top of his class from *Boise Codeworks – Immersive Full-Stack* program. His passion for solving problems and building user focused, solution applications motivated him to formally pursue this change in career.

He is an experienced professional with a unique combination of technical expertise, managerial experience, business leadership, and design and production support.

Mr. Coryat has a sincere interest in further expanding his talent to deliver quality software solutions by applying his recent training along with the prior six years of demonstrated strong analytical, leadership, engineering, business, and interpersonal skills.

Skills

Software Development:

- Javascript
- Vue.js
- Node.js
- C#
- .Net
- Dapper
- Bootstrap
- HTML
- CSS
- Axios
- MongoDb
- MySQL

Agile:

- Scrum
- Pair Programming

Mechanical Engineering:

- Solid Works
- Bluebeam
- EXFO OTDR
- Press Brake
- OBD 2 Testing / Diagnostics

- Manual Mill
- Metal Inert Gas (MIG) Welding
- Band Saw
- Plasma Table

Business:

- QuickBooks
- Adobe Photo Shop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft Word
- Microsoft OneNote

Fiber Optics:

- Fiber Optics Testing
- Optical Time-Domain Reflectometer (OTDR) Testing

Leadership:

- Communication
- Organizational
- Motivational
- Decision-making
- Conflict resolution

Professional Experience

Aug. 2020— Nov. 2020

Codeworks

Boise, ID

Full-Stack Software Developer (Student)

- Engaged in a 13-week immersive full-stack application development course including 500+ hours of utilizing both front-end and back-end technologies, software development best practices while creating fully functional real-world applications.
- Participated in team collaboration and prioritization via Agile Scrum framework including scrum ceremonies, daily stand ups, requirement refinements, pair, and individual programming.
- Responsible for effective communication and collaboration with 'product owner' to ensure accurate understanding of requirements.
- Designed, developed, tested / debugged, and implemented multiple full stack applications using Java Script and C#. Below are samples of the applications developed:
 - o Individual Contribution:
 - <u>Keepr</u> a full- stack application that models after Pinterest where a user can create
 picture posts, save them to their vaults as well as save other peoples' pictures to
 their vaults.
 - o Software: Vue.js, .Net, My SQL, Dapper and Auth0.
 - <u>Bug Log</u> a full-stack application that enables users to track bug reports. Users
 can create bugs, view details, create comments and edit if owner of that post.
 Users can also view when posts were created, edited, and closed.
 - o Software: Vue.js, Node.js, MongoDb and Auth0.
 - o Team Collaboration:
 - Pet Pal a mobile application that allows users to search for animals in their region, save the animal to their favorites, view details about the animals as well as email and adopt them.
 - o Software: Vue.js, Node.js, MongoDb and Auth0.

Apr. 2018— Aug. 2020

Versus L.L.C.

Garden City, ID

Lead Fabricator

- Provided lead supervision in the oversight of the activities of the weld shop and performed specialized duties involving welding, and metal, resin, foam, plastic and wood fabrications related mostly to motorsports; however, designs ranged from kale chip packing machines, custom doors and window systems, rifles and electronic targets.
- Reverse engineered, via Solid Works (CAD modeling), parts of custom design and fabrication projects for businesses, inventors, and product developers.
- Performed daily quality control checks and ensured welding and fabrication met the appropriate codes.

- Work involved a wide range of skilled mechanical tasks and the use of specialized equipment and hand tools. Required proficiencies included MIG Welding, Press Brake, Manual Mill, Band Saw, Plasma Table Operation, Assembly, Prototyping and General Machine shop tasks.
- Responsible for accurate interpretation of welding symbols and complete welding tasks as per blueprint specifications.
- Recognized by leadership for attention to detail and quality of work while completing projects early. Projects were completed in accordance with the best-known current manufacturing practices relative to design, materials, strength, quality, durability, safety, and workmanship.
- Built several custom over landing vehicles including a complete tear down and from the frame up build.
- Efficiently manufactured custom metal fabrication projects to a standard of .001 or .0001 of an inch per blueprint while maintaining a safe work environment.
- Acted as a mechanic crew member in the top-speed bio diesel team and competed at the Bonneville Salt Flats.

Jul. 2016— Apr. 2018

Core Fusion L.L.C.

Boise, ID

Co-owner / Founder

Marketing, Sales, Back Office

- Launched new business by developing and executing business and financial plans in collaboration with co-owner.
- Performed office and management duties.
- Performed hiring, training, mentoring, and managing staff.
- Managed marketing, bookkeeping, payroll, and advertising functions.
- Studied the industry market and kept abreast of new trends.
- Requisitioned, assigned, and tracked materials needed for the daily operations.
- Reviewed daily production reports, material usage sheets, kept track of work hours, completed, and maintained accurate "as-built maps" for areas built.
- Verified submitted Daily Production Reports for accuracy and approved recorded production for billing purposes.
- Demonstrated a profitable, six figure revenue in the first year utilizing a four-person team.
- Maintained Customer Relations as well as Job negotiations, Billing and Blueprint Redlines.

Leadership

- Oversaw all operations to ensure that all Splicing operations are completed in accordance with customer and industry specifications. This included ensuring that all employees working on project were working safely and productively.
- Constructed new Builds as well as worked on existing systems.
- Provided OJT training for employees working under my direction on construction practices and methods to ensure a safe and productive work environment.
- Assigned daily production to in-house and subcontract crews.

- Performed audits of Splicing operations to ensure work was being completed in compliance with project specifications and monitored safe work practices.
- Practiced high testing standards and end to end testing.
- Reviewed Splicing and Testing documentation from field, identified deficiencies and addressed with splicers and ensured corrections were promptly completed.

Mar. 2015— Jul. 2016

Spligitty Fiber Optics

Boise, ID

Fiber Splicer Foreman

Customer

- Created confident relationships with customers who, in turn, trusted my leadership and implementation of high risk, high priority cut overs including 911 circuits and Long-Haul TR Fiber Connections projects.
- Responsible for customer satisfaction and interaction with engineers and coordinating with customers and engineers for scope changes and communicating those changes to appropriate personnel.

Leadership

- Managed a six-person fiber splicer team within the Boise Region.
- Responsible for concise, efficient, accurate reporting of project, customer, and personnel status to remote manager from Montana Advanced.
- Spearheaded profit growth in Boise Region by more than 100 percent. This result enabled the team to double in size as well as expand the fleet and corresponding equipment.
- Empowered team members to work together cooperatively while focusing on desired end of one's own or one's units work, setting challenging goals, focusing efforts on the goals and meeting, or exceeding them.
- Delegated jobs on a priority basis as well as matched employees on a skill base per job.
- Ensured employees followed all safety protocols.
- Ensured that information was passed on to others who should be kept informed.

Fiber Splicer

- Accountable for terminating and testing aerial and underground fiber optic systems, updating and maintaining project tracking information such as production sheets, time sheets and customer required paperwork.
- Performed all aspects of projects in accordance with TIA / EIA standards and applicable building codes.
- Responsible for Vehicle up-keep and maintenance.
- Operated on a strong build and test everything to completion system.
- Responsible for doing new builds and cell tower under strict QA requirements.

Education

Certification

Aug. 2020— Nov. 2020

Boise Codeworks

Boise, ID

Certificate of Completion

- Immersive Full Stack 4.0 G.P.A.
- Developer Bootcamp

College

Aug. 2005— Dec. 2006

Boise State University

Boise, ID

References

References available upon request.